prizedb.com 2011-02-14

# privacy_policy

BY VISITING THIS WEBSITE AND REQUESTING INFORMATION, PRODUCTS OR SERVICES THEREON, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT PROVIDE ANY INFORMATION OR USE ANY OF THE SERVICES OR PRODUCTS OFFERED OR PROVIDED ON ANY OF THE WEBSITES REFERRED TO IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. 

PLEASE NOTE: THIS PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES FROM TIME TO TIME AND CHANGES ARE EFFECTIVE UPON POSTING. PLEASE CHECK BACK FREQUENTLY FOR UPDATES AS IT IS YOUR SOLE RESPONSIBILITY TO BE AWARE OF CHANGES. WE DO NOT PROVIDE NOTICES OF CHANGES IN ANY MANNER OTHER THAN BY POSTING THE CHANGES AT THIS WEB SITE.

We take user privacy seriously and make reasonable efforts to protect your privacy. We hope the following Privacy Policy will help you understand how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us on this web site. This policy applies solely to information collected at www.prizeDB.com. prizeDB.com is not responsible for the information collection or privacy practices of Third Party websites or applications. 

**1\. Collection of Information**  
**1.1 Personal Data Collection**  
Only User's email address is collected when users make registration to www.prizeDB.com. In order to use certain portions of the services, however, you may be asked for, or you may choose to provide, certain personal information such as name, phone number, address and similar information. We will not collect your personal information while you use the services unless you provide us or authorize us to collect such information voluntarily. 

Referral emails that you initiate from the "Tell-A-Friend" page of your prizeDB account will be sent by TAF Master which is a 3rd party solution provider for tell-a-friend forms on your behalf and will display your email address and that of TAF Master's. By opting to use this form, you are consenting to TAF Masters terms. If a referral signs up for a prizeDB account, he/she will be subject to the same standards of our Privacy Policy and our prizeDB users. 

**1.2 Survey Information**  
prizeDB.com collects information form individuals by various methods, including, but not limited to, when an individual voluntarily completes a survey, order form, or a registration page either online or offline, or by means of online or offline surveys, order forms, or registration page by Third Parties (collectively, a "Survey"). (As used herein, &quality;online" means using the Internet, including the Websites, and related technologies, and "offline" means by methods other than online, including in person, in the postal mail, using telephones and cell phones, and other similar means.) In the surveys, prizeDB.com or a Third Party (a "Third Party") may ask an individual to provide various information to priceDB.com, which may include his/her name, email address, residential address, postal code, telephone numbers, (including cell phone numbers and carries), birth date, gender, salary range, education and marital status, occupation, employment information and personal and online interests and such other information as may be requested from time to time (together, "Survey Information"). prizeDB.com may also collect information concerning an individual form another source and uses that information in combination with information provided from this web site. Completing the Surveys is completely voluntary, and individuals are under no obligation to provide Survey Information to prizeDB.com or Third Party, but an individual may receive incentives from prizeDB.com or a Third Party in exchange for providing Survey Information to prizeDB.com. 

In order to enhance the service we provide, and to expedite the offer process, we may pre-populate data fields on a third party partner's survey or offer form with the information that you provided to the web site. We may also use certain third party partners to host the survey or offer form and transfer the completed survey or offer form to other third party partners. Third party partners are contractually prohibited from using any information in a pre-populated data field until they have posted a link to the privacy policy of the third party partners/advertiser listed in the applicable offer and you have consented to the transfer of such personal information by consenting to the offer or submitting to the survey. Likewise, third party partners that serve as the host of the survey or offer form are contractually prohibited from using or retaining your personal information for any purpose other than the compilation and transfer of such personal information to our third party partners/advertiser. Once your personal information is transferred to a third party partners your personal information is subject to that partner's privacy policy and prizeDB.com is no longer responsible for use of your personal information by such business partner.

**1.3 Site Membership or Registration**  
To extent registration is required to receive email and possibly postal communications from prizeDB.com, this Privacy Policy also applies to consumers that have agreed to receive e-mail from prizeDB.com, whether at our Website, via email, on Third Party websites, or otherwise. We collect information in certain portions of our Website, where guests provide content submissions and suggestions or participate in interactive online activities (i.e. by way of responding to questions and surveys, community listing, ratings, searches and comparison searches, bidding, purchasing, chat, games, or bulletin boards, etc.) The personal profile information you submit to prizeDB.com remains your property, but submitting that information to us, you grant us the right to use that information for marketing purposes. prizeDB.com may also use such information for content improvement and feedback purposes. We may sell the personal information that you supply to us and we may join together with other businesses to bring selected retail opportunities to our members. There businesses may include providers of direct marketing services and applications, including lookup and reference, data enhancement, suppression and validation. In addition, prizeDB.com reserves the right to release current or past member information in the event prizeDB.com believes that the membership is being or has been used in violation of the Rules or to commit unlawful acts, if the information is subpoenaed, if prizeDB.com is sold or acquired, or when prizeDB.com deems it necessary or appropriate. By agree to these terms, you hereby consent to disclosure of any record or communication to any Third Party when prizeDB.com in its sole discretion, determines the disclosure to be appropriate. 

"Subscription" occurs when an end-user registers for prizeDB.com's services, either via registration at our website, via co-registration at a marketing partner's website, or via a permission pass/ opt-out/ no-opt mailing prizeDB.com collects personally identifiable information about out subscribers, based on: information gathered at the time of registration, subscriber interaction and response to subsequent electronic mailings and website use, information provided by marketing partners, and information appended form data aggregators. Information collected may include, but is not necessarily limited to: name, email address, postal address, gender, birth date, telephone number, activity, interests, user behavior and other demographic information. This information enables us to better tailor our content to subscriber's needs and to help our clients to promote and sell their products and services. 

With your consent, prizeDB.com may from time to time send commercial e-mails with additional offers and products. prizeDB.com is committed to ethical and responsible e-mail practices. Accordingly, prizeDB.com strives to make sure that all commercial e-mails sent by prizeDB.com are compliant with the Can-Spam Act of 2003. Members may opt-out of receiving promotional mailings by clicking on the opt-out link contained in the body of any commercial e-mail sent by prizeDB.com or by unsubscribing from commercial e-mail by logging into your Member account on prizeDB.com, clicking on the unsubscribe link placed at the bottom of the page and entering the e-mail address that you wish to unsubscribe from further commercial e-mail message from prizeDB.com We only allow one account per household. This rule exists to protect our advertising partners, as it serves to engender high quality, unique leads. Potential users who reside in households with multiple people are recommended to share an account. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Site. If your personally identifiable information changes, you may update it by logging into your account on prizeDB.com and clicking on the Account link. To deactivate an account, please contact our Customer Service directly to make further action. 

**1.4 Cookies and Other Info Collected Using Technology**  
PrizeDB.com currently uses cookie to associate certain Internet-related information about an individual in our database. Additionally, prizeDB.com may use other new and evolving sources of information in the future (together, "Technology Information").

(a) Cookies.  
A cookie is a small amount of data stored on the hard drive of the individual's computer that allows prizeDB.com to identify the individual with his or her corresponding data that resides in prizeDB.com's database. You may read more about cookies at http://cookiecentral.com. Individuals who use the Websites need to accept cookies in order to use all of the features and functionality of the Websites. 

(b) New Technology.  
The use of technology on the Internet, including cookies, is rapidly evolving, as is prizeDB.com's use of new and evolving technology. As a result, prizeDB.com strongly encourages individuals to revisit this policy for any updates regarding its use of technology. 

(c) Usage Tracking.  
prizeDB.com tracks information related to the electronic mailings and web pages viewed by users and subscribers, as well as the hyperlinks clicked by subscribers, while viewing our emails or visiting our websites. 

(d) Log Files.  
Log files are used to track and monitor subscriber usage. 

(e) Log Files.  
Log files are used to track and monitor subscriber usage.Optional Registration

(f) Feedback and Inquiries.  
You have the ability to contact prizeDB.com to provide us with their feedback. prizeDB.com uses this information to respond to you and analyze customer service issues. 

**1.5 Outside Information**  
prizeDB.com may receive information about individuals from Third Parties or from other sources of information outside of prizeDB.com including information located in public databases ("Outside Information").

**1.6 Individual Information**  
As used herein, Individual Information means Survey Information, Third Party List Information, Other Information, Technology Information, and Outside Information, and any other information prizeDB.com gathers or receives about individuals.

**1.7 No Information Collected from Children**  
prizeDB.com will never knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If prizeDB.com obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database. Because it does not collect such information, prizeDB.com has no such information to use or to disclose to Third Parties. prizeDB.com has designed this policy in order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). 

**1.8 Credit Card Information**  
prizeDB.com may in certain cases collect credit card numbers and related information, such as the expiration date of the card ("Credit Card Information") when an individual places an order from prizeDB.com. When the Credit Card Information is submitted to prizeDB.com, such information is encrypted and is protected with SSL encryption software. prizeDB.com will use the Credit Card Information for purposes of processing and completing the purchase transaction, and the Credit Card Information will be disclosed to Third Parties only as necessary to complete the purchase transaction. 

**1.9 Links to External Websites**  
prizeDB.com's emails and websites contain links to external websites. You will be taken to external websites if you click on these links. Your information may be passed from prizeDB.com's database to the external website, and/or external database, for your convenience (e.g. your information may be used to pre-fill a form at a destination website). prizeDB.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any external website owner. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any website they visit. 

**2\. Use of Individual Information**

**2.1 Discretion to Use Information**  
THE COMPANY MAY USE INDIVIDUAL INFORMATION FOR ANY LEGALLY PERMISSIBLE PURPOSE IN COMPANY'S SOLE DISCRETION. 

The following paragraphs in Section 2 describe how prizeDB.com currently uses Individual Information, but prizeDB.com may change or broaden its use at any time. As noted below, prizeDB.com may update this policy from time to time. prizeDB.com may use Individual Information to provide promotional offers to individuals by means of email advertising, telephone marketing, direct mail marketing, online banner advertising, and package stuffers, among other possible uses. 

**2.2 Email and Unsubscribe Policy**  
prizeDB.com uses Individual Information to provide promotional offers by email to individuals. prizeDB.com may maintain separate email lists for different purposes. If email recipients wish to end their email subscription from a particular list, they need to follow the instructions at the end of each email message to unsubscribe from the particular list. 

prizeDB.com's unsubscribe process impacts only the future delivery of electronic mailings disseminated by prizeDB.com on its own behalf. You may still receive electronic mailings sent on behalf of Third Parties and your personal information may still be shared with Third Parties for use in offline marketing and data appends, including email appends. 

You should also note that unsubscribing from prizeDB.com's electronic mailings will not automatically unsubscribe the subscriber's information from any Third Party associates and licensees of the data. Since Third Party associates and licensee partners maintain separate databases from prizeDB.com, and you will need to unsubscribe from each source individually, if desired. This allows you the freedom to pick and choose which subscriptions to maintain and which to discontinue. 

**2.3 Content of Email Messages**  
In certain commercial email messages sent by prizeDB.com, an Advertiser's name will appear in the "From:" line but hitting the "Reply" button will cause a reply email to be sent to prizeDB.com. The "Subject:" line of prizeDB.com email messages will usually contain a line provided from the Advertiser to prizeDB.com. 

**2.4 Solicited Email**  
prizeDB.com only sends email to individuals who, by registration as a member to one of it's websites, have agreed to receive email and email solicitations from prizeDB.com, one of prizeDB.com's websites or who have agreed on Third Party websites to receive email from prizeDB.com, it's agents, affiliates, subsidiaries or from third parties. As such, prizeDB.com does not send unsolicited email messages and certain statutes requiring certain formatting for unsolicited email are not applicable to prizeDB.com' email messages. 

**2.5 Targeted Advertising**  
prizeDB.com uses Individual Information to target advertising to an individual. When an individual is using the Internet, prizeDB.com uses Technology Information (see also Section 2.7 below) to associate an individual with that person's Individual Information, and prizeDB.com attempts to show advertising for products and services in which the person has expressed an interest in the Surveys, indicated an interest by means of Technology Information, and otherwise. prizeDB.com may, at its discretion, target advertising by using email, direct mail, telephones, cell phones, and other means of communication to provide promotional offers. 

**2.6 Direct Mail and Telemarketing**  
prizeDB.com uses Individual Information to advertise, directly or indirectly, to individuals using direct mail marketing or telemarketing using telephones and cell phones. 

**2.7 Use of Technology Information**  
prizeDB.com uses Technology Information (1) to match a person's Survey Information and Third Party List Information to other categories of Individual Information to make and improve profiles of individuals, (2) to track a person's online browsing habits on the Internet, (3) to determine which areas of prizeDB.com's websites are most frequently visited. This information helps prizeDB.com to better understand the online habits of individuals so that prizeDB.com can target advertising and promotions to them. 

**2.8 Profiles of Individuals**  
prizeDB.com uses Individual Information to make a profile of an individual. A profile can be created by combining Survey Information and Third Party List Information with other sources of Individual Information such as information obtained from public databases. 

**2.9 Storage of Individual Information**  
prizeDB.com stores the Individual Information in a database on leased computers. Our computers have security measures (such as a firewall) in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under prizeDB.com's control. Not withstanding such measures, prizeDB.com cannot guarantee that its security measures will prevent leased computers from being illegally accessed, and the Individual Information on them stolen or altered.

**3\. Dissemination of Individual Information**

**3.1 Sale or Transfer to Third Parties**  
PRIZEDB.COM MAY SELL OR TRANSFER INDIVIDUAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES FOR ANY PURPOSE IN PRIZEDB.COM'S SOLE DISCRETION.

**3.2 Order Fulfillment**  
prizeDB.com will transfer Individual Information to Third Parties When necessary to provide a product or service that a person orders form such Third Party while using prizeDB.com websites or when responding to offers provided by prizeDB.com.

**3.3 Legal Process**  
prizeDB.com may disclose Individual Information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, and other legal processes. 

**3.4 Summary Data**  
prizeDB.com may sell or transfer non-individualized information, such as summary or aggregated anonymous information about all persons or sub-groups of persons. 

**3.5 Access**  
Individuals have access to their Individual Information collected to provide an opportunity for an individual to correct, amend, or delete such information. Access can be obtained by contacting prizeDB.com Customer Service team. prizeDB.com may also grant advertising clients and email services providers' access to an individual's email address to verify the origin of the Individual Information collected.

**4\. Privacy Practices of Third Parties**

**4.1 Advertiser cookies**  
Advertising agencies, advertising networks, and other companies (together, "Advertisers") who place advertisements on the Websites and on the Internet generally may use their own cookies, and other technology to collect information about individuals. prizeDB.com does not control Advertisers' use of such technology and prizeDB.com has no responsibility for the use of such technology to gather information about individuals. 

**4.2 Links**  
The Websites and email messages sometimes contain hypertext links to the websites of Third Parties. prizeDB.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other websites. Linked websites may contain links to websites maintained by Third Parties. Such links are provided for your convenience and reference only. prizeDB.com does not operate or control in any respect any information, software, products or services available on such Third Party websites. The inclusion of a link to a web site does not imply any endorsement of the services or the site, its contents, or its sponsoring organization. 

**4.3 Affiliated Companies**  
prizeDB.com may disclose, transfer, and sell Individual Information to entities affiliated with prizeDB.com in prizeDB.com's discretion. 

**5\. Unsubscribe Procedures**  
To unsubscribe from a particular list follow the instructions in each promotional email message sent by prizeDB.com.

**If you have questions about this policy, please contact our Customer Service team.**
